I decided to make a plot of subway ridership by day of the week.
ولقد قررت إنشاء رسم يوضح ركاب قطار الأنفاق .حسب اليوم من الأسبوع
The first thing I wanted to do was take a look at the data and
وأول ما أردت القيام به هو إلقاء نظرة على البيانات
remind myself where that information was stored.
وتذكير نفسي بموقع .تخزين هذه المعلومات
And I can see here that it's in the day_week column.
ويمكنني أن أرى هنا .أنها قد خُزنت في العمود the day_week
So the first thing I'm going to do is group the subway data by
ولهذا فإن أول شيء سأقوم به هو تجميع بيانات قطار الأنفاق
the day of the week.
.حسب اليوم من الأسبوع
And as before, this gives me a data frame grouped by object so
وكما سبق، أحصل بهذا على إطار بيانات مصنف حسب الكائنات
I can't really see what's going on yet.
.ولهذا لا يمكنني حقًا أن أرى ما الذي يحدث حتى الآن
Next, I want to take the mean ridership for each day of the week, so
وبعد ذلك، أرغب في استخراج متوسط عدد الركاب&lrm; ،لكل يوم في الأسبوع
I'll add .mean.
.ولهذا سأُضيف .mean
This time, I can see some results.
.وفي هذه المرة، يمكنني أن أرى بعض النتائج
This is showing me the mean value of each column for each day of the week.
تعرض هذه النتائج متوسط قيمة كل عمود .بالنسبة لكل يوم من الأسبوع
I'm specifically interested in the ENTRIESn_hourly column, so
وأشعر باهتمام خاص بالعمود ENTRIESn_hourly ولهذا السبب
I'll look at that one.
.سأُلقي نظرة عليه
And then running this again, I see a series containing only the values for
ثم بتشغيل هذا مرة أخرى، أرى متسلسلة لا تحتوي إلا على
the ENTRIESn_hourly column.
.قيم العمود ENTRIESn_hourly
And I'll name this series ridership_by_day.
وسأُطلق على هذه المتسلسلة اسم .ridership_by_day
Next I'm ready to make a plot of these values.
وبعد ذلك، أنا مستعد لإنشاء رسم .بهذه القيم
As usual I'll use %pylab inline to make sure the plots appear within
،وكالمعتاد سأستخدم %pylab المضمن
the notebook and import seaborn as sns to make my plots look a little nicer.
للتأكد من ظهور رسوماتي .في دفتر الملاحظات واستيراد seaborn كـ sns لتحسين رسوماتي
Next, I'll call ridership_by_day.plot.
.وبعد ذلك، سأُطلق على هذه الرسم اسم ridership_by_day.plot
And this is the plot I get.
.وهذا هو الرسم الذي أحصل عليه
The most striking I notice is that the ridership is significantly
وأهم نقطة ألاحظها هي أن عدد ركاب قطار الأنفاق
lower on days 5 and 6 than during the rest of the week.
ينخفض كثيرًا في اليومين 5 و6 .مقارنة ببقية أيام الأسبوع
Days 5 and 6 are Saturday and Sunday, so this makes sense.
يمثل اليومان 5 و6 يومي السبت والأحد .ولهذا يبدو ذلك منطقيًا